aoclarkejr.com 2010-06-15

# AJ Clarke's Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy for www.aoclarkejr.com**

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at clarkea-10@sandiego.edu.

At www.aoclarkejr.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by www.aoclarkejr.com and how it is used.

**Log Files**  
Like many other Web sites, www.aoclarkejr.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
www.aoclarkejr.com does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**  
.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on www.aoclarkejr.com.  
.:: Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to www.aoclarkejr.com and other sites on the Internet.  
.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

If you have not [opted out of third-party ad serving](https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=94152), the cookies of other [third-party vendors or ad networks](https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=94149) may also be used to serve ads on your site, and should be [disclosed in your privacy policy](https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=94150) as well.

Because publisher sites and laws across countries vary, we’re unable to suggest specific privacy policy language. However, you may wish to review resources such as the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/), or NAI, which suggests the following language for data collection of non-personally identifying information:

> We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

You can find additional information in Appendix A of the [NAI Self-Regulatory principles for publishers](http://www.networkadvertising.org/pdfs/NAI_principles.pdf) (PDF). Please note that the NAI may change this sample language at any time.

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include ….

**Google Adsense**

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.aoclarkejr.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

www.aoclarkejr.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.aoclarkejr.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.
